Nathan Oliver Smith

1774 E Northgate Dr. Apt. 1148 Irving, TX 75062 (636) 346-0195 nsmith1@udallas.edu

Objective

With over three years of experience with python and computational problems, Nathan has developed a keen interest in applied data science. Along with his current research in computational physics, he is also developing his skills in machine learning and data visualization. Currently, he is taking courses on SQL and machine learning algorithms with business applications and is interested in opportunities to grow those skills in a real world environment.

Experience

May 2019 - Present

University of Dallas, Irving - Researcher in Computational Astrophysics

• Currently developing a maximum entropy algorithm in python to map the accretion disks of Cataclysmic Variable Stars based off of data from the Kepler Space Telescope.

June 2018 - August 2018

University of Dallas, Irving - Researcher in Computational Astrophysics

- Developed python programs to filter atmospheric effects from telescope data.
- Wrote scripts to locate over 50,000 binary star system candidates for study. Used this data for a NASA grant application which was accepted.

August 2018 - December 2018

University of Dallas, Irving - *Physics Tutor*

- Employed by the University of Dallas Physics department.
- Tutored college level physics to underclassmen and non-physics majors during the fall semester while maintaining 18 credit hours of classes.

Education

August 2016 - May 2020 (Projected)

University of Dallas, Irving - Bachelor of Science, Physics

Includes a study abroad semester in Rome (Spring 2018), traveled to 11 countries.

June 2020 - May 2021 (Projected)

University of Dallas, Irving - Masters of Business Administration

The 4+1 MBA program allows a student to take prerequisites classes during senior year and receive an MBA in one year's time.